Gross, Robert; Papers apap291
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Robert Gross Papers
1973-1997
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap291
10.85 cubic ft.
This collection includes materials created or collected during Robert (Bob) Gross' work with the organizations National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty and Journey of Hope...from Violence to Healing as well as the Lighting the Torch of Conscience initiative.
Collection X
Biographical History
Robert (Bob) Gross is a death penalty abolitionist who has worked with the National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty (NCADP), where he served as associate director, Journey of Hope...from Violence to Healing, and other organizations in opposition to capital punishment. Gross was also extremely active with the Lighting the Torch of Conscience abolitionist campaign.
Scope and Contents
The records were created or collected during Gross' work with the National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty (NCADP), Journey of Hope...from Violence to Healing, Lighting the Torch of Conscience, and other activities in opposition to the death penalty.
The NCADP leads and coordinates the movement to end state killing in the United States. Its 120 member organizations include civil and human rights groups, legal advocacy and public interest groups, and virtually every major church or religious denomination in the country. Journey of Hope...from Violence to Healing is an organization that is led by murder victims' family members. It conducts public education speaking tours and addresses alternatives to the death penalty.
The collection includes NCADP administrative materials, state files, programs, and organizations; Journey of Hope...From Violence to Healing administrative files, videotapes, photographs, and press packets related to speaking tours; and material from the Lighting the Torch of Conscience march in 1990.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is processed and all four series are arranged alphabetically.
Acquisition Information
Bob Gross donated this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives in 2007.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted with the exception of a small number of files notes in Series 1 and 3.
Death Penalty; Capital punishment--Political aspects.; Political activists--United States; Gross, Bob; Correspondence; Files by subject; Fliers (printed matter)
- National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, Administration, 1977-1995; 1; 1.8 cubic ft.
  Scope and Contents
  This series features administrative national files for the National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty (NCADP). There are materials on national events such as Abolition Day and Fastathon, as well as national newsletters, including execution alerts. The NCADP bylaws and director's list are also included.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  - Abolition Day- 1987, 1986-1987; Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abolition Day- 1987, Activities, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Abolition Day- 1988, 1987-1988; Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Abolition Day- 1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Advisory Committee, 1987; 1989; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annual Reports, 1986-1987; 1989; 1991; 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Articles- Appeals, 1985; 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Articles- Crime and Criminal Justice Issues, 1985-1987; Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Articles- Death Penalty, 1979; 1983-1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Articles- Individual Cases, 1986-1987; Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Articles- NCADP, 1985-1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Attitudes- Death Penalty, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bank Records- FY 1987, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Must consult with in archivist before viewing this material.
  - BVS Projects- F.O., 1991-1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bylaws, 1984-1986; 1989-1990; 1993; Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Cartoons- Death Penalty, 1986; 1988; 1990-1993; Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Christian Retreat Registration, 1991-1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence- NCADP, 1985-1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence- People on Death Row, 1983-1993; Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence- People Not on Death Row, 1983-1985; 1988-1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence- U.S. Congressional Representatives and Senators, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - The Death Penalty: The Religious Community Calls for Abolition, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Death Penalty Day, 1985; Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Death Penalty Day- 1986, Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Death Penalty Exchange Newsletter, 1986-1993; 1995; Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Death Penalty Fiction, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Death Penalty Poetry, 1986-1987; 1990; Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Death Row Act, 1986; 1992-1993; Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Declaration of Life, 1993; Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Development Committee, 1986-1987; 1991-1994; Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Director Information, 1990; Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Director of Organizations, 1983-1985; 1987; 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Execution Alerts- 1987 and Earlier, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Execution Alerts- 1988 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Execution Alerts- 1989, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Execution Alerts- 1990 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Execution Alerts- 1991 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Execution Alerts- 1992 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Execution- Lists, 1990-1991; Undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Executive Committee- Agenda and Minutes, 1982-1990; 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Executive Committee- Agenda and Minutes, 1984-1987; Undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Executive Committee- Correspondence, 1985-1994 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Expenses and Mileage Reports, 1989-1995; Undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Expenses Reports, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Facts Series, 1988-1989; Undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Fast ADP, 1985; 1987-1990; Undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Fastathon- 1987, Undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Fastathon- 1988, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Fastathon- 1989, Undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Federal Death Penalty- In Practice, Undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Federal Death Penalty- U.S. Sentencing Commission, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Federal Legislation- 1986 and Earlier, 1985-1986; Undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Federal Legislation- 1987 and 1988, 1987-1988; Undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Federal Legislation- 1989 and 1990, 1989-1990; Undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Federal Legislation- 1991 and 1992, 1991-1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Federal Legislation- 1993, Undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Federal Legislation- 1994, Undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Financial- Bank Records 1988, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    Must consult with an archivist before viewing this material.
  - Financial- Bank Records 1989, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Financial- Bank Records 1990, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Financial- Bank Records 1991 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Financial- Bank Records 1992, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Financial- Bank Records 1993, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Financial- Bank Records 1994 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Financial Projections, 1985-1990; Undated (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - First Execution Packet, 1987-1990; Undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Fundraising- Events, 1983; 1987-1991; 1994; Undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Fundraising- Direct Mail Results, 1989-1994; Undated (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - General Committees, 1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Goals- 1985, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Goals- 1986 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - IRS 501 c3- Letters, 1985-1986; 1992; Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Legislative Handbook Folder, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Life Squads, 1990-1991; Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Logo, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Murder Victims' Families Committee, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - NCADP Budget, 1985-1994; Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Nominations, 1987-1995; Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Not in Our Names", 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Office Space, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Op-Ed, 1979; 1984-1994; Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Organizing Against the Death Penalty - Second Edition, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Organizing Against the Death Penalty - Third Edition, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Outreach Committee, 1986; 1990; Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - People Don't Want the Death Penalty/ Politicians Do, 1989-1993 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Personnel, 1985; 1989; 1995; Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Postal Permit Correspondence, 1983; 1985-1986; Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Program Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Public Opinion Work, 1983; 1990-1992; Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Quotes, 1987; 1991-1992; Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Regions, 1985-1986; 1989; Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Regions- Northeast, 1986; Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Regions- Western, 1985-1986; Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Religious- Catholic Statements, 1980-1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Religious Community Committee, 1985-1990; Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Religious Community Committee, 1992-1993; Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Religious Community Committee- Post LTC, 1989-1993; Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Religious- Death Penalty Resources for Vigil, Worship, and Education, 1977; 1979; 1982; 1984-1993; Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Religious- National Statements, 1982; 1987-1990; 1993; Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Religious Leaders Groups, 1984; 1986; Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Religious - Statewide Community Statements, 1985-1987; 1992; Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Religious- Study Resources, 1980; 1985; 1987-1990; Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Spanish Translations, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Staff Reports, 1985; 1987; 1989; Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Staff Retreat, 1989-1993; Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - State Info- Master Copies, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - State Targeting, 1987-1988; Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Washington Office, 1990-1991; 1993; Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
- National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, Subject Files, 1973-1995; 2; 5.2 cubic ft.
  This series features files organized by state that relate to groups focused on abolishing the death penalty. In addition to the state groups, there are some Puerto Rican, U.S. national, and Canadian organizations included. Correspondence from the Lighting the Torch of Consciousness initiative, including some with Bob Gross, is significant within this series.
  - Alabama Correspondence, 1983-1984; 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alabama Meeting, 1992-1993; Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alabama Miscellaneous, 1984; 1991-1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alabama- Other Organizations, 1983-1985; 1990; 1993; 1995; Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alabama Prison Project, 1983-1994; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alabama- Project Hope, 1989-1990; 1992-1994; Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alaska Correspondence, 1983; 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alaska- Lighting the Torch of Conscience, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Arizona- Capital Punishment Project, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Arizona Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Arizona- Lighting the Torch of Conscience, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Arizona Miscellaneous, 1987-1989; 1991-1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Arizona- Other Organizations, 1989; 1991-1993; Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Arkansas- Arkansas Coalition Against the Death Penalty, 1981; 1989; 1991; 1993; Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Arkansas Correspondence, 1984; 1987; Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Arkansas Miscellaneous, 1981; 1984; 1986-1987; 1989-1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Arkansas- Lighting the Torch of Conscience, 1989; Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Arkansas- Organizations, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Arkansas- Other Organizations, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - California- March Against State Killing, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - California Correspondence, 1982-1986; 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - California- East Bay Justice Project, 1984-1987; 1989; Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - California- Friends Committee on Legislation, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - California Humanities, 1990-1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - California- Information Clearinghouse on Criminal Justice, 1987; Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - California- Lighting the Torch of Conscience, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - California Legislation, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - California Miscellaneous, 1980-1987; Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - California Miscellaneous, 1988-1993; Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - California- National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, 1988-1994; Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - California- Northern California Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, 1984-1987; 1991-1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - California- Southern California Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, 1984-1994; Undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Canada- Capital Punishment Study Guide, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Canada- Coalition Against the Return of the Death Penalty, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Canada Correspondence, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Canada Miscellaneous, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Canada Organization, Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Canada- Release, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Colorado- Coalition Against the Death Penalty, 1983-1991; 1993; Undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Colorado Correspondence, 1983-1984; 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Colorado Miscellaneous, 1984; 1988; Undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Colorado- Other Organizations, 1984; 1993; Undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Connecticut Correspondence, 1980; 1983-1984; 1986 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Connecticut- Lighting the Torch of Conscience, 1989-1990; Undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Connecticut Miscellaneous, 1980; 1987; 1989; 1991; Undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Connecticut- Network to Abolish the Death Penalty, 1980; 1983; 1987-1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Connecticut- Other Organizations, 1980; 1986; Undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Delaware- American Civil Liberties Union, 1989; Undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Delaware Correspondence, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Delaware Miscellaneous, 1980; 1989; 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - District of Columbia- Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, 1982-1985; Undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - District of Columbia Correspondence, 1981; 1983-1984; 1986 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - District of Columbia Miscellaneous, 1982; 1984; 1989; 1991-1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - District of Columbia- Other Organizations, 1981; 1982; 1984; Undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Florida- Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty and Clearinghouse on Criminal Justice, 1982-1993; Undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Florida Correspondence, 1983-1984; 1986; 1991; Undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Florida- Impact and Alternatives in Research of Shalom, 1986-1987; 1989; Undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Florida- Lighting the Torch of Conscience, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Florida- March to Abolish the Death Penalty, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Florida Miscellaneous (1 of 2), 1979; 1983-1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Florida Miscellaneous (2 of 2), 1979; 1983-1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Florida- Other Organizations, 1982-1986; 1988-1989; 1994; Undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Florida- Statewide Death Penalty Conference, 1977; 1982-1983; Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Florida- Willie Darden Information Packet, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Georgia- Clearinghouse, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Georgia- Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, 1992; 1994; Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Georgia- Committee Against the Death Penalty, 1980-1981; 1984; 1986-1987; Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Georgia Correspondence, 1983-1985; 1987; Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Georgia- Konini, 1993-1994; Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Georgia Miscellaneous, 1973; 1981; 1983-1987; 1992; Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Georgia- New Hope House, 1989-1994; Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Georgia- Other Organizations, 1980-1983; 1985-1987; 1989; Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Georgia- Southern Prison Ministry, 1985; 1987-1990; 1992 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Georgia- Southern Prisoners Defense Committee, 1984-1987; Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Hawaii- Organizations, 1987; 1991; Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Idaho Miscellaneous, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Illinois- Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, 1980-1983; 1985-1994; Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Illinois Correspondence, 1981-1986; 1989-1990; Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Illinois- Information Week, 1990-1991; Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Illinois- Lighting the Torch of Conscience, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Illinois Miscellaneous, 1981; 1983-1987; 1990; Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Illinois- Organizations, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Illinois- Organizations, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Illinois- Organizations, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Illinois- Organizations, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Illinois- Organizations, 1989-1995; Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Iowa- Civil Liberties Union, Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Iowa- Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, 1990-1993; 1995; Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Iowa Correspondence, 1983-1985; 1987; 1993 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Iowa- Lighting the Torch of Conscience, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Iowa Miscellaneous, 1987-1988; 1991-1993; Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Iowa- Other Organizations, 1989-1991; Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Kansas- Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty (1 of 2), 1981; 1985-1994; Undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Kansas- Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty (2 of 2), 1981; 1985-1994; Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Kansas Correspondence, 1983; 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Kansas Miscellaneous, 1981; 1985-1987; 1991; 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Kansas- Other Organizations, 1985; 1995 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Kentucky- Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, 1985-1992; Undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Kentucky Correspondence, 1981; 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Kentucky- Lighting the Torch of Conscience, 1989; Undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Kentucky Miscellaneous, 1983-1986; 1993; Undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Louisiana- Citizens Against the Death Penalty and Coalition on Jails and Prisons, 1982-1983; Undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Louisiana Correspondence, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Louisiana- Lighting the Torch of Conscience, 1990; Undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Louisiana Miscellaneous, 1979-1993; Undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Louisiana- Other Organizations, 1984; 1986-1989; Undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Louisiana- Pilgrimage on Life, 1983-1995; Undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Maine- Civil Liberties Union, Undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Maine Correspondence, 1986-1987; 1991-1992; Undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Maine- Lighting the Torch of Conscience, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Maine- Mainers Against the Death Penalty, 1991-1992; Undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Maine Miscellaneous, 1990-1991; Undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Maryland- Coalition Against the Death Penalty, 1982-1984; Undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Maryland Correspondence, 1983-1984; 1990; Undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Maryland- Let Live, Undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Maryland Miscellaneous, 1984; 1986-1987; 1989; 1993-1995; Undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Maryland- Other Organizations, 1986; 1989; Undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Maryland- Quixote Center, Undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Massachusetts- Citizens Against the Death Penalty, 1981-1986; 1989-1992; Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Massachusetts Correspondence, 1984; 1986; 1992 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Massachusetts- Lighting the Torch of Conscience, 1989; Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Massachusetts Miscellaneous, 1982; 1984; 1991-1992; Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Massachusetts- Northeastern University, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Massachusetts- Other Organizations, 1984; Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Michigan- American Friends Service Committee, 1982; 1984-1986; Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Michigan- Coalition Against the Death Penalty, 1983; 1985-1986; 1988-1989; 1993; Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Michigan Correspondence, 1983-1984; 1986; 1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Michigan- Council on Crime and Delinquency, 1988-1990; 1992 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Michigan- Lighting the Torch of Conscience, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Michigan Miscellaneous, 1978; 1985; 1987-1989; Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Michigan- Other Organizations, 1974; 1981; 1984; 1989-1990; Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Minnesota- Civil Liberties Union, 1987; 1989; Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Minnesota Correspondence, 1983-1986; 1989-1992; Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Minnesota- Lighting the Torch of Conscience, 1989; Undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Minnesota Miscellaneous, 1987; 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Minnesota- Other Organizations, 1988-1989; Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Mississippi- Coalition Against the Death Penalty, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Mississippi Correspondence, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Mississippi Miscellaneous, 1983; 1991 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Mississippi- Other Organizations, 1983; 1992; Undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Missouri- Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, 1983-1984; 1988; 1991-1992; Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Missouri Correspondence, 1983; 1985-1987; 1990 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Missouri- Eastern Missouri to Abolish the Death Penalty, 1989-1994; Undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Missouri- Lighting the Torch of Conscience, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Missouri Miscellaneous, 1983-1984; 1986; 1989-1990; 1993 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Missouri- Other Organizations, 1983; 1988-1989; Undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Montana- American Civil Liberties Union, Undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Montana- Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty, 1988-1991; Undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Montana Correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Montana Miscellaneous, 1989; Undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Montana- Other Organizations, 1981; 1989 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - National- Amnesty International, Analysis of Attitudes in Florida on the Death Penalty, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - National- Amnesty International, Attitudes in Florida on the Death Penalty, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - National- Amnesty International, Attitudes in Oklahoma on the Death Penalty, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - National- Amnesty International, General, 1989; 1990-1991; 1993; Undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - National- Amnesty International, Offices, 1984-1989; Undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - National- Amnesty International, USA The Death Penalty Briefing, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - National- Catholics Against Capital Punishment, 1992-1993; Undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - National- Clearing House on Death Penalty Legislation, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - National- C.U.R.E., 1987-1989; 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - National- Equal Justice, USA, 1986-1992; 1994; Undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - National-Frontline with Sister Helen Prejean, Matthew Poncelet, Undated (Video-tape 12)
  - National- Just-Life, 1987; 1989-1990; 1992 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - National- Justice Fellowship, 1985; Undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - National- Mennonite Central Committee, U.S., 1982; 1984; 1987-1993; Undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - National- Mennonite Central Committee, U.S., Undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - National- NAACP Legal Defense Fund, 1987; 1989; Undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - National- National Alliance Against Racist and Political Repression, 1987-1988; 1990; 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - National- National Association of Sentencing Advocates, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - National- National Black Police Association, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - National- National Committee to Reopen the Rosenberg Case, 1983; 1988-1994; Undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - National- National Interreligious Task Force on Criminal Justice, 1985-1989; Undated (Box 3, Folder 53)